Register of the Joseph Hansen Papers, 1887-1980.
Hoover Institution Archives
- CORRESPONDENCE, 1913-1980
  - Hansen, Beatrice (sister-in-law of Joseph Hansen)
    - 1967
      - May-December (Folder 8)
    - 1968-1969 (Folder 9)
  - Hansen, Conrad D. (brother of Joseph Hansen), 1928-1977 (Folder 10)
  - Hansen, Conrad J. Z. and Rose (father and mother of Joseph Hansen)
    - 1928-1940 (Box 17, Folder 1)
    - 1941-1942 (Folder 2)
    - 1943-1948 (Folder 3)
    - 1950-1964 (Folder 4)
    - 1965-1967 (Folder 5)
    - 1968-1970 (Folder 6)
    - 1971-1974 (Folder 7)
    - 1975-1978 (Folder 8)
  - Hansen, David and Ellarean (brother and sister-in-law of Joseph Hansen), 1928-1976 (Folder 9)
  - Hansen, Reba (wife of Joseph Hansen)
    - 1929 (Box 18, Folder 1)
    - 1930-1936 (Folder 2)
    - 1937
      - February-August (Folder 3)
      - September-October (Folder 4)
      - November (Folder 5)
      - December (Folder 6)
    - 1938
      - January (Folder 7)
      - February (Folder 8)
      - March (Folder 9)
      - April (Folder 10)
      - May (Folder 11)
      - June-August (Folder 12)
    - 1939
      - October (Box 19, Folder 1)
      - November (Folder 2)
      - December (Folder 3)
    - 1940 (Folder 4)
    - 1941 (Folder 5)
    - 1942 (Folder 6)
    - 1943
      - February-April (Folder 7)
      - May (Folder 8)
      - June (Box 20, Folder 1)
      - July (Folder 2)
      - August (Folder 3)
      - September (Folder 4)
      - October (Folder 5)
      - November-December (Folder 6)
    - 1944 (Folder 7)
    - 1945 (Folder 8)
    - 1948
      - January (Box 21, Folder 1)
      - July-August (Folder 2)
    - 1951-1956 (Folder 3)
    - 1957 (Folder 4)
    - 1958-1961 (Folder 5)
    - 1962
      - January-March (Folder 6)
      - April (Folder 7)
    - 1964-1967 (Folder 8)
    - 1968 (Folder 9)
    - 1969-1977 (Folder 10)
  - Hansen family (other members). See also DeWolfe, Louise
    - 1913-1943 (Folder 11)
    - 1960-1978 (Folder 12)
  - Harding, Timothy (U.S.; Brazil), 1960-1974 (Box 22, Folder 1)
  - Harer, Asher and Ruth, 1953-1978 (Folder 2)
  - Harris, Alan and Connie (Great Britain)
    - 1963-1969 (Folder 3)
    - 1970-1975 (Folder 4)
    - 1976-1980 (Folder 5)
  - Haston, Jock (Great Britain), 1977 (Folder 6)
  - Healy, Gerry (Great Britain)
    - 1953-1962 (Folder 7)
    - 1963 (Folder 8)
  - Herreshoff, David, 1977 (Folder 9)
  - Herron, Edwin, Rosamond, and Nausicaa. Includes satirical drawings by Edwin Herron
    - 1937-1939 (Folder 10)
    - 1940-1947 (Folder 11)
    - 1966-1967 (Folder 12)
    - 1970-1973 (Box 23, Folder 1)
    - 1974 (Folder 2)
    - 1975 (Folder 3)
    - 1976 (Folder 4)
    - 1977
      - January-May (Folder 5)
      - June-December (Folder 6)
    - 1978
      - January-May (Folder 7)
      - June-December (Folder 8)
    - 1979-1980 (Box 24, Folder 1)
  - Horowitz, Gus, and Finch, Becky (U.S.; France), 1966-1977 (Folder 2)
  - Houdek, Julia, 1961-1966 (Folder 3)
  - Hutter, Trent, 1956-1958 (Folder 4)
  - Jack, Anna (South Africa; Canada), 1965-1967 (Folder 5)
  - James, Frances, 1954-1957 (Folder 6)
  - Jenkins, Mark (Great Britain), 1975-1976 (Folder 7)
  - Jhaveri, Sharad (India), 1970-1977 (Folder 8)
  - Jones, Alan (Great Britain), 1974-1978 (Folder 9)
  - Jordan, Pat (Great Britain), 1962-1978 (Folder 10)
  - Jungclas, Georg (Germany), 1957-1972 (Folder 11)
  - Karsner, Rose
    - 1937-1943 (Folder 12)
    - 1950-1953 (Folder 13)
    - 1954-1957 (Folder 14)
    - 1958-1959 (Folder 15)
    - 1960-1961 (Box 25, Folder 1)
    - 1962-1965 (Folder 2)
    - 1966-1968 (Folder 3)
  - Kaye, Clara, 1953-1957 (Folder 4)
  - Kemp, Tom (Great Britain), 1958-1961 (Folder 5)
  - Kerry, Karolyn, 1962-1980 (Folder 6)
  - Kerry, Tom
    - 1942-1962 (Folder 7)
    - 1963 (Folder 8)
    - 1964 (Folder 9)
    - 1965 (Folder 10)
  - Khrushchev, Nikita (Soviet Union), 1956 (Folder 11)
  - Klein, Mark, 1957-1958 (Folder 12)
  - Kolpe, S. B. (India), 1960-1974 (Folder 13)
  - Kurihara, Toichi (Japan), 1966-1968 (Folder 14)
  - Lambert, Pierre (France), 1962-1976 (Box 26, Folder 1)
  - LaRouche, Lyndon, 1954 (Folder 2)
  - Lee, Franz J. T. (Germany; re South Africa), 1964-1969 (Folder 3)
  - Leninist-Trotskyist Faction (Fourth International), 1977 (Folder 4)
  - Levine, Isaac Don, 1959-1968 (Folder 5)
  - Lippmann, Walter, 1971-1976 (Folder 6)
  - Locke, Keith (Canada; New Zealand), 1968-1971 (Folder 7)
  - Lovell, Frank and Sarah, 1943-1979 (Folder 8)
  - Lund, Caroline (U.S.; Belgium), 1969-1976 (Folder 9)
  - Lund, Gordon (U.S.; Germany), 1929-1957 (Folder 10)
  - McAvoy, Clifford, 1957 (Folder 11)
  - Macdonald, Dwight, 1938-1939 (Folder 12)
  - Mage, Shane, 1957-1959 (Folder 13)
  - Maitan, Livio (Italy)
    - 1960-1965 (Folder 14)
    - 1966-1967 (Folder 15)
    - 1968-1969 (Folder 16)
    - 1970-1972 (Folder 17)
    - 1973-1978 (Folder 18)
  - Malagon, Alberto (Dominican Republic), 1967-1975 (Folder 19)
  - Malamuth, Charles, 1939-1940 (Folder 20)
  - Mandel, Ernest (Belgium)
    - 1945-1965 (Folder 21)
    - 1966 (Box 27, Folder 1)
    - 1967 (Folder 2)
    - 1968 (Folder 3)
    - 1969 (Folder 4)
    - 1970 (Folder 5)
    - 1971 (Folder 6)
    - 1972-1973 (Folder 7)
    - 1974-1975 (Folder 8)
    - 1976-1979 (Folder 9)
  - Mandel, Gisela (Germany; Belgium)
    - 1967-1969 (Folder 10)
    - 1970 (Folder 11)
    - 1971-1973 (Folder 12)
    - 1974-1976 (Folder 13)
    - 1977 (Box 28, Folder 1)
    - 1978-1980 (Folder 2)
  - Marcy, Sam, 1955 (Folder 3)
  - Martin, Jeanne (France), 1948-1955 (Folder 4)
  - Medvedev, Zhores (Soviet Union; Great Britain), 1974 (Folder 5)
  - Meissenheimer, Joyce (South Africa; Canada), 1971 (Folder 6)
  - Mills, C. Wright, 1961 (Folder 7)
  - Moreno, Nahuel (Argentina)
    - 1961-1965 (Folder 8)
    - 1966-1970 (Folder 9)
    - 1971-1974 (Folder 10)
    - 1975-1977 (Folder 11)
  - Morgan, Bill and Ada, 1939-1957 (Folder 12)
  - Morgan, Jeanne, 1952-1956 (Folder 13)
  - Morrell, Andrea, 1971-1972 (Folder 14)
  - Morrow, Felix, 1939-1940 (Folder 15)
  - Moustakis, Chris, 1940-1953 (Folder 16)
  - Mqotsi, L. (South Africa; Zambia; Great Britain), 1966-1971 (Folder 17)
  - Nasir, George (Canada), 1956-1961 (Folder 18)
  - Nattier, Luc (France), 1966-1971 (Folder 19)
  - Novack, George
    - 1937-1951 (Folder 20)
    - 1955-1962 (Folder 21)
    - 1963-1964 (Box 29, Folder 1)
    - 1965-1975 (Folder 2)
  - O'Brien, Vaughan T. (U.S.; Mexico), 1937-1977 (Folder 3)
  - O'Connor, Harvey, 1957 (Folder 4)
  - Okatani, S. (Japan), 1963-1971 (Folder 5)
  - Olson, Vernel (Canada; re Cuba), 1965-1972 (Folder 6)
  - O'Rourke, Walter (U.S.; Mexico), 1939-1942 (Folder 7)
  - Pablo, Michel (Greece; France), 1960-1963 (Folder 8)
  - Pearce, Brian (Great Britain), 1959-1960 (Folder 9)
  - Peng, Shu-tse, and Ch'en, Pi-lan (China; France; U.S.)
    - 1960-1966 (Folder 10)
    - 1967 (Folder 11)
    - 1968-1969 (Folder 12)
    - 1970-1971 (Folder 13)
    - 1972-1973 (Box 30, Folder 1)
    - 1974-1979 (Folder 2)
  - Perry, Hayden, 1971 (Folder 3)
  - Preis, Art and Ethel, 1956-1965 (Folder 4)
  - Prensa Latina (Cuba; Czechoslovakia), 1960-1970 (Folder 5)
  - Ramirez, Alfonso (Venezuela), 1961-1976 (Folder 6)
  - Ramirez, Socorro (Colombia), 1977-1978 (Folder 7)
  - Reed, Evelyn, 1940-1965 (Folder 8)
  - Reyes, Ezequiel (Argentina), 1961-1962 (Folder 9)
  - Riddell, John (Canada), 1972 (Folder 10)
  - Ring, Harry, 1956-1979 (Folder 11)
  - Ring, Priscilla, 1956-1980 (Folder 12)
  - Roberts, Dan, 1956-1961 (Folder 13)
  - Roberts, Holland, 1957-1958 (Folder 14)
  - Roberts, Steve and Demila, 1944-1980 (Folder 15)
  - Robinson, Gladys Lloyd, ca. 1939 (Folder 16)
  - Rodolf, Frank and Katherine, 1973-1979 (Folder 17)
  - Romero, Ramon (Mexico), 1962 (Folder 18)
  - Rosas Bravo, Manuel (Venezuela), 1961 (Folder 19)
  - Sakai, Yohichi (Japan), 1967-1974 (Box 31, Folder 1)
  - Samarakkody, Edmund (Sri Lanka), 1964-1971 (Folder 2)
  - Santen, Sal (Netherlands), 1946-1960 (Folder 3)
  - Savelli, Giulio (Italy), 1966-1973 (Folder 4)
  - Schein, Ruth
    - 1963-1975 (Folder 5)
    - 1976-1980 (Folder 6)
  - Schmidt, Lester F., 1949 (Folder 7)
  - Schoenman, Ralph (U.S.; Great Britain), 1966 (Folder 8)
  - Schultz, Henry, 1938-1952 (Folder 9)
  - Schwartz, Stephen, 1971-1972 (Folder 10)
  - Seiffert, Johannes Ernst (Germany; Japan), 1966-1970 (Folder 11)
  - Selander, Ted and Dot, 1948-1962 (Folder 12)
  - Sell, Evelyn, 1958-1966 (Folder 13)
  - Shachtman, Max, 1934-1938 (Folder 14)
  - Sharon, Art (U.S.; Europe)
    - 1943-1965 (Folder 15)
    - 1966
      - January-May (Folder 16)
      - June-September (Folder 17)
      - October-December (Folder 18)
    - 1967
      - January-April (Folder 19)
      - May-December (Box 32, Folder 1)
    - 1968 (Folder 2)
    - 1969-1978 (Folder 3)
  - Shaw, Ed, 1963-1974 (Folder 4)
  - Sheppard, Barry (U.S.; Europe), 1965-1978 (Folder 5)
  - Shriver, George, 1962-1976 (Folder 6)
  - Simon, Jean, 1957-1970 (Folder 7)
  - Simon and Schuster (Publishers), 1937-1941 (Folder 8)
  - Sinclair, Louis (Great Britain), 1958-1976 (Folder 9)
  - Slaughter, Cliff (Great Britain), 1975 (Folder 10)
  - Snipper, Ann, 1969-1980 (Folder 11)
  - Socialist Workers Party. National Committee, 1939-1951 (Folder 12)
  - Socialist Workers Party. Political Committee, 1939-1940 (Folder 13)
  - Star, Jessica, 1972-1973 (Folder 14)
  - Steele, John and Sheila (Great Britain; Canada), 1970-1971 (Folder 15)
  - Steiger, George von (Switzerland), 1962-1972 (Folder 16)
  - Stein (France), 1971 (Folder 17)
  - Stein, Morris and Sylvia, 1948-1976 (Folder 18)
  - Sterling, Max, 1935-1937 (Folder 19)
  - Stermer, Joe, 1958-1970 (Folder 20)
  - Swabeck, Arne, 1946-1959 (Box 33, Folder 1)
  - Tampoe, Bala (Sri Lanka), 1971-1976 (Folder 2)
  - Tarbuck, Ken (Great Britain), 1966-1970 (Folder 3)
  - Tate, Ernest (Great Britain; Canada)
    - 1966-1967 (Folder 4)
    - 1968-1976 (Folder 5)
  - Thornett, Alan (Great Britain), 1975-1976 (Folder 6)
  - Thorstad, David (U.S.; France), 1966-1967 (Folder 7)
  - Thurber, Joe, 1928 (Folder 8)
  - Trainor, Lawrence and Augusta
    - 1941-1942 (Folder 9)
    - 1943 (Folder 10)
    - 1944 (Folder 11)
    - 1953-1979 (Folder 12)
  - Trejos, Marta (Costa Rica), 1975-1979 (Folder 13)
  - Trotskaia, Nataliia Sedova (Soviet Union; Mexico)
    - 1940-1946 (Folder 14)
    - 1947-1951 (Folder 15)
    - 1952-1957 (Box 34, Folder 1)
  - Trotsky, Leon (Soviet Union; Mexico)
    - 1937-1939 (Folder 2)
    - 1940 (Folder 3)
  - United States. Consulate General (Mexico City), 1940 (Folder 4)
  - Valencia, Horacio (Argentina), 1962-1970 (Folder 5)
  - Valenzuela, Humberto (Chile), 1963 (Folder 6)
  - Van Heijenoort, Jean (France; Mexico; U.S.), 1939-1941 (Folder 7)
  - Vern, Dennis, 1951 (Folder 8)
  - Vitale, Luis (Chile), 1960-1975. Includes letters written collectively to, or collectively by, Vitale and Humberto Valenzuela (Folder 9)
  - Volkov, Esteban (Mexico), 1960-1976 (Folder 10)
  - Wald, Alan, 1976-1978 (Folder 11)
  - Wang, Fan-hsi (China; Great Britain), 1978 (Folder 12)
  - Warshell, Steve, 1971-1979 (Folder 13)
  - Wasserman, Jac, 1937 (Folder 14)
  - Weber, Jack and Sara, 1939-1977 (Folder 15)
  - Weinstock, Nathan (U.S.; France), 1967-1975 (Folder 16)
  - Weiss, Murry
    - 1937-1956 (Folder 17)
    - 1957-1962 (Folder 18)
  - Weiss, Myra Tanner, 1940-1957 (Folder 19)
  - Weiss, Suzanne, 1973-1979 (Folder 20)
  - Weissman, George and Connie
    - 1947-1962 (Box 35, Folder 1)
    - 1963-1969 (Folder 2)
  - Weston, Carol (U.S.; Latin America), 1962 (Folder 3)
  - Weyl, Sylvia, 1958 (Folder 4)
  - Whitney, W. J. and Lillian (Canada), 1955-1962 (Folder 5)
  - Wicks, Harry (Great Britain), 1977 (Folder 6)
  - Widick, B. J., 1936-1937 (Folder 7)
  - Wohlforth, Tim, 1957-1977 (Folder 8)
  - Wright, John G., 1939-1955 (Folder 9)
  - Yamanishi, Eichii (Japan), 1957-1965 (Folder 10)
- SPEECHES AND WRITINGS, 1928-1978.
  Note: Socialist Workers Party is abbreviated throughout this series as SWP
  - College papers, University of Utah, ca. 1928-1932. Typescript and holograph class papers, together with some curricular material
    - Courses on the novel (Box 35, Folder 11-12)
    - Courses on the short story (Folder 13)
    - Courses on sociology (Folder 14)
    - Miscellaneous courses (Folder 15)
  - Imaginative writings, ca. 1928-1940
    - Novels
      - "All That a Man Has"
        - Typescript (Box 36, Folder 1-5)
        - Draft pages (Folder 6-7)
        - Notes and publisher's report (Folder 8)
      - "Dusty Sun." Typescript (Folder 9-11)
    - Poems
      - General. Typescripts (Folder 12)
      - "Night," Reimei, 1932 November. Printed copy (Folder 13)
      - "100% Unaffiliated," Utah Humbug, 1933 May. Printed copy (Folder 14)
    - Short stories. Typescripts unless otherwise specified
      - Fragments and brief descriptive pieces. Typescripts and holographs (Box 37, Folder 1)
      - "Across Low Hills" (Folder 2)
      - "Alby Stringfellow" (Folder 3)
      - "Alias Podder Puff" (Folder 4)
      - "And Cherish" (Folder 5)
      - "The Autopsy of Nelly Carter" (Folder 6)
      - "A Boat Ride" (Folder 7)
      - "Bristol Wells," University Pen, 1933 Winter. Printed copy (Folder 8)
      - "Business Not So Good," Frontier and Midland, 1934 Autumn. Printed copy (Folder 9)
      - "Carmel and Clara" (Folder 10)
      - "Charlemagne Bendoble." Holograph and typescript (incomplete) (Folder 11)
      - "Confusion Range" (Folder 12)
      - "Dahlgren" (Folder 13)
      - "Dave Comes to Dinner," Frontier and Midland, 1935 Summer. Printed copy (Folder 14)
      - "Deep Is the Night, Splendid the Sun" (Folder 15)
      - "The Dish Rag," University Pen, 1931 December. Typescript and printed copy (Folder 16)
      - "Donovan and Gary," Frontier and Midland, 1935 Autumn. Printed copy (Folder 17)
      - "Dross" (Folder 18)
      - "End of the Trail" (Folder 19)
      - "Five Hours in the Sun" (Folder 20)
      - "Fly Swatter Hop" (Folder 21)
      - "Forgotten Chapter" (Folder 22)
      - "Frivolous Venus" (Folder 23)
      - "From the Blue Grill" (Folder 24)
      - "Girl without a Veil" (Folder 25)
      - "Graveyard on the Hill," University Pen, 1933 Spring. Printed copy (Folder 26)
      - "Hall of Eternity" (Folder 27)
      - "The Hobo Kid" (Folder 28)
      - "I Am My Beloved's" (Folder 29)
      - "A Kick in the Gaskin" (Folder 30)
      - "Lord Fondleroy's Mother." Holograph and typescript (Folder 31)
      - "The Lovers" (Folder 32)
      - "Man Swinging a Hammer," Frontier and Midland, 1936 Winter. Printed copy (Folder 33)
      - "Moccasins of the Corpse" (Box 38, Folder 1)
      - "Moon Shadows" (Folder 2)
      - "Mrs. Bishop Loses Her Ring" (Folder 3)
      - "Night Came Again" (Folder 4)
      - "Night Crept over the Alley" (Folder 5)
      - "On the Ledge" (Folder 6)
      - "One Hundred Thousand Years" (Folder 7)
      - "Passion Dance" (Folder 8)
      - "Poetic Justice" (Folder 9)
      - "Poisoned Water" (Folder 10)
      - "Room to Room" (Folder 11)
      - "A Rose for the Grave" (Folder 12)
      - "Servant of God" (Folder 13)
      - "Silhouette," University Pen, 1932 March. Typescript and printed copy (Folder 14)
      - "Slime" (Folder 15)
      - "A Souvenir for the Old Folks" (Folder 16)
      - "Speed--Spree" (Folder 17)
      - "The Success" (Folder 18)
      - "Svart Erick on Qvitvare" (Folder 19)
      - "Taken from My Life" (Folder 20)
      - "They of Yomso" (Folder 21)
      - "This the Land of Sterility" (Folder 22)
      - "Torture of the Red Carnation" (Folder 23)
      - "A Tragedy in Black" (Folder 24)
      - "Trickling Sand" (Folder 25)
      - "Twisted Mountain" (Folder 26)
      - "Two Wooden Doves" (Folder 27)
      - "Unrest" (Folder 28)
      - "The Witch of Endor" (Folder 29)
      - "X13 over S93" (Folder 30)
  - "Remarkable Parallel" (re Moscow Trials), ca. 1930s. Typescript (Folder 31)
  - Workers Party of the U.S. school notes, ca. 1935 (Folder 32)
  - "The Communist Manifesto, "1936. Outline notes (Folder 33)
  - "French People's Front," 1936. Outline notes for speech (Folder 34)
  - "French Situation," 1936. Outline notes for speech (Folder 35)
  - Speech on Franklin D. Roosevelt, 1936. Outline notes (Folder 36)
  - "Unity Maneuvers of the Third International," 1936. Outline notes for speech (Folder 37)
  - Outline notes on maritime trade union fraction meeting, ca. 1936-1937 (Folder 38)
  - Report on maritime trade unions, ca. 1936-1937. Typescript. Authorship uncertain (Folder 39)
  - "Stalinist Purge Hits Western Worker, " ca. 1936-1937. Typescript (Folder 40)
  - " 1936 Maritime Strike," 1937. Outline notes and partial holograph of speech (Folder 41)
  - Notes on neutrality legislation and Spanish Civil War, 1937 (Folder 42)
  - Notes on Albert Parsons (Haymarket martyr), ca. 1937 (Box 39, Folder 1-2)
  - "People's Front," 1937. Outline notes for speech (Folder 3)
  - Speech on sit-down strikes, 1937. Outline notes and partial typescript (Folder 4)
  - Notes, 1937 May 12-June 12 (Folder 5)
  - Notes on Socialist Party, 1937 July (Folder 6)
  - "Coyoacan Local of the Fourth International," 1938. Notes for internal SWP speech (Folder 7)
  - "The Russian Workers' Own Story," Socialist Appeal, 1938 September 17. Review of Boris Silver, The Russian Workers' Own Story. Printed copy (Folder 8)
  - Article on asylum of Leon Trotsky in Mexico for Socialist Appeal, 1938 November 12. Typescript (Folder 9)
  - "Gold Is Still Where You Find It," New International, 1938 December. Review of John Littlepage and Demaree Bess, In Search of Soviet Gold. Printed copy (Folder 10)
  - Election campaign position statement on New York City subways, 1939. Typescript (Folder 11)
  - Notes on fascism, ca. 1939 (Folder 12-17)
  - Notes, miscellaneous, 1939 (Folder 18)
  - Speech on fascism, ca. 1939. Outline notes (Folder 19)
  - Speech on Christian Front, 1939 August 23. Notes and flyer (Folder 20)
  - Notes on SWP National Committee plenum, 1939 September 30 (Folder 21)
  - Notes on Russian question, 1939 November (Folder 22)
  - "On the New York Election Platform," 1939 December 7. Typescript (Folder 23)
  - "Report on Invitation of Dies Committee to L. Trotsky to Testify before It on History of Stalinism," 1939 December 14. Typescript (Folder 24)
  - Notes on World War II, ca. 1939-1941 (Box 40, Folder 1-2)
  - Notes on maritime trade unions, ca. 1940s (Folder 3)
  - Notes, miscellaneous, ca. 1940s (Folder 4)
  - "Comparison with Bourgeois Wars," 1940. Typescript (Folder 5)
  - Notes on Labour and Socialist International, 1940 (Folder 6)
  - Notes on Leon Trotsky and Coyoacan household, 1940 (Folder 7)
  - Notes on World War II, 1940 (Folder 8)
  - "Renunciation of the Class Criterion," 1940. Typescript (Folder 9)
  - "Roundup" (re World War II), 1940. Typescript (incomplete) (Folder 10)
  - Speech on Leon Trotsky, 1940. Notes and partial typescript (Folder 11)
  - Speech notes and other notes, internal SWP debates, 1940 (Folder 12)
  - Speech, SWP Bronx branch, 1940 January. Notes (Folder 13)
  - Speech on World War II, 1940 January. Holograph and typescript (Folder 14)
  - Speech on internal SWP dispute, SWP Yorkville branch, 1940 January 3. Typescript (incomplete) (Folder 15)
  - Speech on internal SWP dispute, SWP Bronx branch, 1940 January 10. Notes and partial typescript (Folder 16)
  - Speech on internal SWP dispute, SWP Bronx branch, 1940 February. Notes (Folder 17)
  - Notes on SWP New York City meeting, 1940 February 18 (Folder 18)
  - "The Menace of the Christian Front," 1940 March. Typescript (Folder 19)
  - Report to SWP Bronx branch on internal SWP dispute, 1940 March 14. Notes and partial typescript (Folder 20)
  - Notes on Provisional May Day Committee Conference (organized by Communist Party), 1940 March 29 (Folder 21)
  - Speech notes and other notes, SWP national convention, 1940 April 5-8 (Folder 22)
  - May Day speech, 1940 May 1. Holograph (Folder 23)
  - Press releases on assassination of Leon Trotsky, 1940 August 21. Typescripts (in English and Spanish) (Folder 24)
  - Press release on Communist Party statements re assassination of Leon Trotsky, 1940 September 11. Typescript (Folder 25)
  - Memoir of Leon Trotsky, 1940 November 8. Typescripts (Folder 26)
  - "The Revolutionary Way Out," 1940 December 20. Outline notes for speech, and flyer (Folder 27)
  - "Go Forward," ca. 1940-1941. Typescript (incomplete) (Folder 28)
  - "Burnham: A Budding Fascist," 1941. Review of James Burnham, The Managerial Revolution. Typescript (Folder 29)
  - "What Is Trotskyism?" 1941. Outline notes for speech (Folder 30)
  - Introduction for Grace Carlson, V. I. Lenin memorial meeting, 1941 January 24. Typescript (Box 41, Folder 1)
  - "The Soviet Union and the War," 1941 March 30. Outline notes and partial typescript of speech, and flyer (Folder 2)
  - May Day message for Inicial, 1941 April 23. Typescript (Folder 3)
  - Speech, Leon Trotsky memorial meeting, 1941 August 22. Typescript (Folder 4)
  - "The Educational Tasks Facing the Party," 1941 October. Notes and typescript of speech at internal SWP meeting (Folder 5)
  - "The Soviet Union and the War," 1941 November 8. Outline notes and partial typescript of speech, and announcement (Folder 6)
  - Article on American entry into World War II, 1941 December. Galleys (Folder 7)
  - Notes on Antigua, 1941 December 20 (Folder 8)
  - Article on World War II, 1942. Galleys (Folder 9)
  - "Caribbean Cruise," 1942. Typescript (Folder 10)
  - "Fascism in America," ca. 1942. Outline notes for speech (Folder 11)
  - "Fascism in Italy," ca. 1942. Outline notes for speech (Folder 12)
  - "German Fascism," ca. 1942. Outline notes for speech (Folder 13)
  - "Military Front," 1942. Typescript (Folder 14)
  - Notes on Russian front in World War II, ca. 1942 (Folder 15)
  - "The Relationship of Our Transition Program to the Coming Revolution," 1942. Outline notes for speech at internal SWP meeting (Folder 16)
  - "What Is the Principled Question at the Bottom of the Discussion?" 1942 February. Typescript (Folder 17)
  - "A Planet Writhing in Agony," 1942 May. Typescript (Folder 18)
  - Notes, 1943 (Folder 19)
  - Report on SWP educational work, 1943 March 4. Notes for oral report at internal SWP meeting (Folder 20)
  - Speech, Leon Trotsky memorial meeting, 1943 August 22. Notes (Folder 21)
  - Speech notes and other notes, SWP National Committee plenum, 1943 October 29 (Folder 22)
  - Speech, SWP National Committee plenum, 1943 November 1. Outline notes and typescript (Folder 23)
  - Speech, SWP internal meeting, Buffalo, New York, 1943 December 5. Outline notes (Folder 24)
  - Notes taken while accompanying James P. Cannon to prison, 1943 December 28-31 (Folder 25)
  - "A New Contribution to Marxism," 1944. Review of James P. Cannon, The History of American Trotskyism (originally intended as introduction to book). Typescripts (Folder 26)
  - Notes, 1944 (Folder 27)
  - "How the Trotskyists Went to Jail," Fourth International, 1944 February. Typescript (Folder 28)
  - "Notes re Criticism of 'How the Trotskyists Went to Jail, '" 1944 March. Holograph (Folder 29)
  - Notes on meeting with leaders of Revolutionary Communist Party (Great Britain), 1944 May 30 (Folder 30)
  - Notes on SWP national convention, 1944 November 16 (Folder 31)
  - "Our Method and Theirs," 1944 November 19. Notes and typescript of speech at SWP national convention (Folder 32)
  - "Labor's Need: An Independent Labor Party," 1944 December 17. Outline notes and partial typescript of speech at internal SWP meeting (Folder 33)
  - "Greece," 1945. Notes (Folder 34)
  - Introduction to Leon Trotsky, The First Five Years of the Communist International, 1945. Typescripts (Folder 35)
  - "Mind," 1945. Notes (Folder 36)
  - Notes on Albert Goldman, 1945 (Folder 37)
  - Notes, miscellaneous, 1945 (Folder 38)
  - Speech on Soviet victory in World War II, 1945. Outline notes (Box 42, Folder 1)